Bijula Joy RN BSN

812 Del Lenora Drive #45 Duncanville, Texas, 75116 6193156850 bijulajoy86@gmail.com

Summary

Registered Nurse with 10 years of RN experience in variety of health care settings in various countries, specialised in Emergency Medicine, and Medical surgical nursing. Gained valuable experience over the years by practising in Rehab, Mental Health Nursing and Geriatric medicine. Seven years of Emergency Nursing experience in the country Of Canada. Currently works as Stroke and pulmonary specialised nurse in a highly reputed hospital in the State of Texas. Highly professional, competent and skilled and up to date with required certifications Like ACLS, BLS and NIHS Stroke assessment certified, Tele monitoring Certified

Education

Rajiv Gandhi University Of Health Sciences, Bengaluru, KARNATAKA Bachelor of Science In Nursing

Graduated - November 2007

SB college of Nursing

TEXAS BOARD OF NURSING,

License in Texas

Current Active RN License in Texas.

Employment History

Methodist Charlton Medical Center, Dallas, Texas

Registered Nurse

February 2018 - Present

Enrolled - April 2017

Works as a specialised Nurse in Stroke and Pulmonary Nurse, Efficient knowledge in recognising and managing patients present with Stroke symptoms and their way to recovery. Also works on a daily basis with Patients with Respiratory conditions, who presents with advance airways, Tracheostomy and Chest tube. Certified in Managing patients with Tele Monitoring

Indira Gandhi Co-operative Hospital

STAFF NURSE December 2007 - August 2008

Worked in the Medical and surgical floor as a certified RN

Saudi Medical Services, Al Salam Hospital

Emergency RN September 2008 - July 2009

Worked as an Emergency RN in highly Busy ER Deals with high level acuity Traumas, like Gun shot wounds, Explosion injuries, Motor vehicle injuries and Burns. Specialised more in the triage room and Trauma room, dealt with transferring patients to OR and also worked in the division of emergency room deals with Emergency deliveries and gynaecological emergencies. Experienced Paediatric resuscitation unit and hydration unit.

Interlake-Eastern Regional Health Authority, Selkirk, Manitoba

Registered Nurse, Emergency

December 2011 - January 2018

Experienced RN in Emergency department, Certified in Canadian triage and acuity, Certified ACLS, BLS, PALS, TNCC From Canada. worked as full time and casual Emergency RN in various Hospitals in IERHA, Canada

Selkirk Mental Health Centre, Selkirk, Manitoba

Registered Nurse

April 2017 - January 2018

assessing and talking to patients about their problems and discussing the best way to plan and deliver their care; building relationships with patients to encourage trust, while listening to and interpreting their needs and concerns; ensuring the correct administration of medication, including injections, and monitoring the results of treatment; responding to distressed patients in a non-threatening manner and attempting to understand the source of distress; applying 'de-escalation' techniques to help people manage their emotions and behaviour; preparing and participating in group and/or one-to-one therapy sessions, both individually and with other health professionals;

BETEL HOME FOUNDATION

REGISTERED NURSE CASUAL

May 2017 - January 2018

Developed, implemented, and evaluated nursing care plan for geriatric patients. Directed and managed activities of health care assistants and subordinate nurses, as assigned. Administered correct medications and delivered appropriate medical interventions, efficiently. Observed and recorded patients' responses to their individual plan of care. Handled and responded to treatment and nursing care related queries of patients and their families. Attended and participated in various health promotion and education activities. Oversaw and assisted with delivery of excellent and safe nursing care to aged patients.

Hobbies & Interests

Reading, Continuous learning

Professional Skills

REGISTERED NURSE: Expert

IV Cannulation: Expert

NG tube insertion: Expert

Catheterisation: Expert

Code Blue, Code Stroke: Expert

Triaging: Advanced

Languages

English: Fluent